Go down
انزل
Resign from humble position
الاستقالة من المنصب المتواضع
Very good
جيد جدًا
Princess Seiya falls in love with Yuan'er
الأميرة سييا تقع في حب يوان إير
Yes, empress
نعم يا إمبراطورة
This is a great joy
هذه فرحة عظيمة
The emperor attaches great importance to toast
يولي الإمبراطور أهمية كبيرة للخبز المحمص
If he could marry the chieftain's daughter
لو كان بإمكانه الزواج من ابنة الزعيم
That can be regarded as the glory of my Ulanara family.
يمكن اعتبار ذلك مجد عائلتي أولانارا.
Yuan'er finally got through it
لقد نجحت يوان إير في النهاية في تجاوز الأمر
yes
نعم
The queen wants to get involved
الملكة تريد التدخل
If you don't take action, it will be over
إذا لم تتخذ أي إجراء، فسوف ينتهي الأمر
you
أنت
stop
قف
The slave meets Princess Seiya
العبد يلتقي بالأميرة سييا
you
أنت
Did I see you next to Jing Yuan yesterday?
هل رأيتك بجانب جينغ يوان بالأمس؟
Princess Seiya has a good memory
الأميرة سيا لديها ذاكرة جيدة
I am a maid in the queen's palace
أنا خادمة في قصر الملكة
I'm very familiar with Mr. Jing.
أنا أعرف السيد جينغ جيدًا.
That's good
هذا جيد
my warrior
محاربي
Let me wait until he finishes his official duties
دعني أنتظر حتى ينتهي من واجباته الرسمية
Come with me to visit the capital again
تعالوا معي لزيارة العاصمة مرة أخرى
I can't wait
لا استطيع الانتظار
You take me to find him
تأخذني للبحث عنه
Princess Seiya comes with me
الأميرة سيا تأتي معي
Princess Seiya, please come here
الأميرة سييا، من فضلك تعالي إلى هنا
Even on the verge of death, you still speak harshly.
حتى على حافة الموت، لا تزال تتحدث بقسوة.
Say it quickly
قلها بسرعة
Let you see the cruel side of Mr. Jing
دعك ترى الجانب القاسي للسيد جينغ
It would be weird if you were still interested in him
سيكون من الغريب أن تظل مهتمًا به
who
من
Meet the princess
تعرف على الأميرة
My warriors don’t need to be polite
لا يحتاج محاربي إلى أن يكونوا مهذبين
Why did you bring the princess to the Sentence Division?
لماذا أحضرت الأميرة إلى قسم الحكم؟
It's bloody and dirty here
إنه دموي وقذر هنا
In case you disturb the princess...
في حالة إزعاج الأميرة...
Mr. Jing doesn’t blame her
السيد جينغ لا يلومها
I asked her to bring me here
طلبت منها أن تحضرني إلى هنا
I'm not afraid
أنا لست خائفا
Strict judiciary
القضاء الصارم
The country can be strong
يمكن للبلد أن يكون قويا
Me too
أنا أيضاً
I got to appreciate a different side of the Qing Dynasty
لقد تمكنت من تقدير جانب مختلف من سلالة تشينغ
It’s rare for a princess to come to the capital
من النادر أن تأتي أميرة إلى العاصمة
Please don’t stay here in Xiaguan
من فضلك لا تبقى هنا في شياغوان
delay time
وقت التأخير
yes
نعم
I'm just here to invite Mr. Jing
أنا هنا فقط لدعوة السيد جينغ
Accompany me to visit the capital
رافقني لزيارة العاصمة
this…
هذا…
Let's go, let's go
دعنا نذهب، دعنا نذهب
princess you
أميرتي انت
Be careful
احرص
Sugar-coated haws
الزعرور المغطى بالسكر
what is that
ما هذا؟
This is
هذا هو
Our unique candied haws in Central Plains
زعرورنا المسكر الفريد في السهول الوسطى
Children's food
طعام الأطفال
So beautiful
جميلة جدا
I have never seen it on the plateau
لم أرى ذلك على الهضبة من قبل
Is it tasty
هل هو حسن الطعم
You try it
انت تحاول ذلك
Um
واحد
Sweet and delicious
حلوة ولذيذة
Are you afraid that I won’t be enough to eat?
هل أنت خائف من أن لا يكون لدي ما يكفي من الطعام؟
Did you buy two skewers specially?
هل اشتريت أسياخين خصيصًا؟
It's so kind of you
هذا كرم منك
I specially left the biggest one for you.
لقد تركت لك الأكبر خصيصًا.
Kei Oto Kei Oto
كي أوتو كي أوتو
What's wrong with Mr. Jing?
ما هو الخطأ مع السيد جينغ؟
Are you okay?
هل أنت بخير؟
Adult Kei
كي البالغ
If you feel unwell
إذا كنت تشعر بتوعك
Let's go back to the palace first
دعونا نعود إلى القصر أولاً
I just left the palace and I have to go back.
لقد غادرت القصر للتو ويجب أن أعود.
I'm fine
أنا بخير
Don't spoil the princess's mood
لا تفسد مزاج الأميرة
Let's continue shopping
دعونا نستمر في التسوق
good
جيد
Lin'er
لين
Came just in time
جاء في الوقت المناسب
Fuku adult
فوكو بالغ
We are shopping
نحن نتسوق
What a coincidence
يا لها من مصادفة
I will come back with my mother-in-law to offer incense.
سأعود مع حماتي لتقديم البخور.
Just happened to see you
لقد حدث أن رأيتك
We are traveling to the capital with Princess Seiya
نحن نسافر إلى العاصمة مع الأميرة سيا
Together?
معاً؟
When you visit the capital, you should look for me.
عندما تزور العاصمة يجب عليك أن تبحث عني.
princess seia
الأميرة حتى
The streets and alleys of this capital city
شوارع وأزقة هذه العاصمة
I grew up playing
لقد نشأت وأنا ألعب
Walking with birds and playing with crickets
المشي مع الطيور واللعب مع الصراصير
Listen to a play and watch shadow puppets
استمع إلى مسرحية وشاهد الدمى الظلية
Eat roast duck and make the donkey roll around
تناول البط المشوي واجعل الحمار يتدحرج
You’ll be entertained for three days and three nights
سوف تستمتع لمدة ثلاثة أيام وثلاث ليالٍ
I don’t even want to go back to the palace
أنا لا أريد حتى العودة إلى القصر
Really
حقًا
Um
واحد
Then how about we go together?
إذن ماذا عن أن نذهب معًا؟
this
هذا
Mr. Fu came at the right time
لقد جاء السيد فو في الوقت المناسب
The official is feeling unwell
المسؤول يشعر بتوعك
Afraid of spoiling the princess’s mood
خائفة من إفساد مزاج الأميرة
Why don't you ask Mr. Fu?
لماذا لا تسأل السيد فو؟
Let's go shopping with the princess
دعنا نذهب للتسوق مع الأميرة
Let's go Princess Seiya
هيا بنا يا الأميرة سيا
Take a look, take a look, take a look
ألق نظرة، ألق نظرة، ألق نظرة
you look happy
تبدو سعيدا
Let's all do it together
دعونا نفعل ذلك جميعا معا
Green peppers Roasted green peppers
الفلفل الأخضر الفلفل الأخضر المشوي
Look
ينظر
Who did I bring?
من أحضرت؟
princess seia
الأميرة حتى
You came just in time
لقد أتيت في الوقت المناسب
We are having a barbecue
نحن نقيم حفل شواء
Are you tired after a day of walking around the capital?
هل تشعر بالتعب بعد يوم من المشي حول العاصمة؟
Sit down, sit down
اجلس، اجلس
Please take a seat
من فضلك اجلس
Listen to Ertai
استمع إلى إرتاي
Princess Huanzhu is the pistachio of the Qing emperor
الأميرة هوانزو هي الفستق لإمبراطور تشينغ
Always come up with fun ideas
دائما تأتي بأفكار ممتعة
I'm not the only one with pistachios
أنا لست الوحيد الذي لديه الفستق
And Lin'er
و لينير
Lin'er, you should sit down too
لين إير، يجب عليك الجلوس أيضًا
Lin'er just taught us a word
لقد علمتنا لين إير للتو كلمة واحدة
called barbecue ladder
يسمى سلم الشواء
Ladder?
سُلُّم؟
alright
على ما يرام
Now that everyone is here
الآن وقد أصبح الجميع هنا
Then let's get started
إذن فلنبدأ
good
جيد
Why doesn’t Mr. Jing come?
لماذا لا يأتي السيد جينغ؟
He hasn't rested yet, okay?
إنه لم يستريح بعد، أليس كذلك؟
Good luck to the fifth elder brother
حظا سعيدا للأخ الأكبر الخامس
Good luck to Princess Princess
حظا سعيدا للأميرة الأميرة
Good luck to you, Mr. Fu
حظا سعيدا لك، السيد فو
Good luck to Princess Seya
حظا سعيدا للأميرة سيا
Okay, okay
حسنا حسنا
Good luck, good luck, get up soon
حظا سعيدا، حظا سعيدا، استيقظ قريبا
Xie Gege
شي جيجي
Mr. Jing is still handling official duties at the Shenxing Department
السيد جينغ لا يزال يتولى مهامه الرسمية في قسم شنشينغ
I specially asked the little one to bring good wine and food.
لقد طلبت من الصغير بشكل خاص أن يحضر النبيذ الجيد والطعام.
Princess Seiya please taste it first
الأميرة سيا من فضلك تذوقيه أولاً
Wait for Mr. Jing to finish handling his official duties.
انتظر حتى ينتهي السيد جينغ من أداء واجباته الرسمية.
Then personally apologize to Princess Seiya
ثم اعتذر شخصيًا للأميرة سييا
Okay okay
حسنا حسنا
This princess has long been hungry and tired
لقد كانت هذه الأميرة جائعة ومتعبة لفترة طويلة
Don't wait for Mr. Jing
لا تنتظر السيد جينغ
Let's eat first
دعونا نأكل أولا
Wait until Master Jing comes
انتظر حتى يأتي السيد جينغ
I have to punish him by drinking three glasses of wine
يجب أن أعاقبه بشرب ثلاثة أكواب من النبيذ
no problem
لا مشكلة
Small resignation
استقالة صغيرة
Then it starts
ثم يبدأ
cheers
هتافات
Cheers Cheers Cheers
هتاف هتاف هتاف هتاف
We sing what Lin'er taught us
نحن نغني ما علمنا إياه لين إير
when
متى
Let us live a life of ease in the world of mortals
فلنحيا حياةً هانئةً في عالم البشر
Riding horses galloping to share the prosperity of the world
ركوب الخيول الراكضة لتقاسم رخاء العالم
Sing to the wine and express the joy in your heart
غنِّ للنبيذ وعبّر عن الفرح في قلبك
Seize the youth with vigor and vitality
اغتنام الشباب بالحيوية والنشاط
What's wrong with Lin'er?
ما هو الخطأ مع لين'ير؟
fine
بخير
- I just burned my eyelids - Princess Seiya, please let me do it.
- لقد أحرقت جفوني للتو - الأميرة سيا، من فضلك اسمحي لي أن أفعل ذلك.
Don't hurt yourself, right?
لا تؤذي نفسك، أليس كذلك؟
This is a slave's job
هذه وظيفة العبد
How do you know the slaves of Shufangzhai?
كيف تعرف عبيد شوفانغزاي؟
They all climbed onto the master’s head
لقد صعدوا جميعا على رأس السيد
Sing happily with the master
غنِّ بسعادة مع المعلم
This princess has no choice but to do it herself
ليس أمام هذه الأميرة خيار سوى أن تفعل ذلك بنفسها
What to say
ماذا أقول
We don’t have anything in Shufangzhai
ليس لدينا أي شيء في شوفانغزاي
Master, slave, etc.
السيد، العبد، الخ.
we are all family
نحن جميعا عائلة
Just like when we were in the courtyard
تمامًا كما كان الحال عندما كنا في الفناء
It is said that the Qing Dynasty was a country of etiquette.
يقال أن سلالة تشينغ كانت دولة الآداب.
He doesn't even distinguish between superiority and inferiority
إنه لا يفرق حتى بين التفوق والدونية
fifth elder brother
الأخ الأكبر الخامس
Am I wrong?
هل انا مخطئ؟
Everyone drank some wine today
لقد شرب الجميع بعض النبيذ اليوم
Discourteous
غير مهذب
I hope the princess will calm down
أتمنى أن تهدأ الأميرة
Lin'er is not a slave
لين إير ليس عبدا
she is my good friend
إنها صديقتي الجيدة
my good friend
صديقي العزيز
Not only can we eat and drink together
ليس فقط يمكننا أن نأكل ونشرب معًا
Can we live and die together?
هل يمكننا أن نعيش ونموت معًا؟
What princess?
أية أميرة؟
Don't even understand
لا أفهم حتى
what did you say
ماذا قلت ؟
little swallow
السنونو الصغير
I just don’t understand anything
انا لا افهم شيئا
You just said you don’t understand anything
لقد قلت للتو أنك لا تفهم شيئا
Little Swallow is fine, fine
السنونو الصغير بخير، بخير
Delicious barbecue is here
الشواء اللذيذ هنا
Okay, okay
حسنا حسنا
Very fragrant
عطرة جدا
how did you bake it
كيف خبزته؟
This is my secret recipe
هذه هي وصفتي السرية
The princess is still angry
الأميرة لا تزال غاضبة
I won't tell you
لن أخبرك
If you dare not tell me
إذا لم تجرؤ على إخباري
I'll tie you back to the plateau
سأربطك مرة أخرى بالهضبة
Go barbecue for me
اذهب للشواء من أجلي
alright
على ما يرام
sit
يجلس
Let's eat
دعونا نأكل
How is your riding skill?
ما هي مهاراتك في الركوب؟
It's no problem to win you
ليس هناك مشكلة في الفوز بك
boast
تباهى
Let’s compete another day
دعونا نتنافس في يوم آخر
Always with you
دائما معك
good
جيد
Give
يعطي
This pair has been matched up, right?
لقد تم مطابقة هذا الزوج، أليس كذلك؟
Done
منتهي
Princess Seiya asked Ertai to be the consort
طلبت الأميرة سيا من إرتاي أن يكون الزوج
Jingyuan
جينغيوان
You ruined a good chess game for me
لقد دمرت لعبة شطرنج جيدة بالنسبة لي
I know my mistake
انا اعرف خطئي
It turns out you are such an obedient child
اتضح أنك طفل مطيع جدًا
who is
من هو
Make you obsessed
تجعلك مهووسًا
I will never forgive you
لن اسامحك ابدا
Wei Chen has been growing up
وي تشين كان يكبر
Follow the queen's arrangements in everything
اتبع ترتيبات الملكة في كل شيء
But love is the only thing that can’t be forced.
لكن الحب هو الشيء الوحيد الذي لا يمكن فرضه.
No matter how hard I try,
بغض النظر عن مدى جهدي،
princess seia
الأميرة حتى
She will only follow her inner choice
إنها لن تتبع إلا اختيارها الداخلي
You are so fooled by me
لقد خدعتني كثيرا
When did you win Seiya's heart?
متى فزت بقلب سييا؟
Those are the only things you have in mind right now
هذه هي الأشياء الوحيدة التي تدور في ذهنك الآن
worthless love love
حب لا قيمة له
empress
إمبراطورة
Not good
ليس جيدا
The emperor wants to make Ziwei his concubine
الإمبراطور يريد أن يجعل زيوي محظية له
Madam, please don’t panic
سيدتي، من فضلك لا داعي للذعر
The slave dares to mention it
العبد يجرؤ على ذكر ذلك
us
نحن
We have one last move
لدينا خطوة أخيرة
Go get Ziwei’s uncles and aunts
اذهب واحصل على أعمام وخالات زيوي
Take it to the Imperial Study Room
خذها إلى غرفة الدراسة الإمبراطورية
yes
نعم
Walk
يمشي
Let's go and see the excitement too
دعونا نذهب ونرى الإثارة أيضًا
Farewell to the Queen Congratulations to the Queen
وداعا للملكة تهنئة للملكة
emperor
الإمبراطور
This slave only has admiration for you
هذا العبد لا يملك إلا الإعجاب بك
A slave cannot be a concubine
لا يجوز للعبد أن يكون محظية
Thoughts of admiration
أفكار الإعجاب
You make tea for me every day
أنت تصنع لي الشاي كل يوم
Play the piano and write poems for me
أعزف على البيانو وأكتب لي قصائد
Could it be
هل يمكن أن يكون
Just think of me as your father
فقط فكر بي كأبيك
Emperor Ama
الإمبراطور أما
Ziwei cannot be your concubine
لا يمكن لزيوي أن تكون محظيتك
little swallow
السنونو الصغير
I have decided
لقد قررت
There's no room for you to talk here
لا يوجد مجال لك للحديث هنا
Emperor Ama
الإمبراطور أما
Ziwei is my sister
زيوي هي أختي
She can't be your concubine
لا يمكنها أن تكون محظيتك
I want to protect her
أريد حمايتها
you
أنت
The Queen has arrived
وصلت الملكة
emperor
الإمبراطور
Ziwei cannot be a concubine
لا يمكن لزيوي أن تكون محظية